{
    "id": "6ffaca68480b470aadefb9b9681a523e",
    "title": "Verbs Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The song ……………………… on an old folk tune.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "based",
                "is based",
                "has based"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The farmer ………………………. when he bought a barren cow.",
            "description": "The farmer didn't cheat. Someone cheated him. Hence, we need the passive verb form here. ",
            "answers": [
                "cheated",
                "has cheated",
                "was cheated"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The balloon ………………………. with a bang.",
            "description": "Burst is the past tense of burst. ",
            "answers": [
                "burst",
                "bursted",
                "bursten"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Good posture ………………………… from holding the backbone straight.",
            "description": "Use the simple present to talk about facts. ",
            "answers": [
                "results",
                "is resulting",
                "resulting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Abraham Lincoln …………………………. from an impoverished background.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to say that something happened in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "comes",
                "has come",
                "came"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Bacteria ………………………… in the air we breathe and in the food we eat.",
            "description": "Bacteria is a plural noun bacterium is the singular form. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The actress ………………………… for her babyish temper tantrums.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "known",
                "knows",
                "was known"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Everyone …………………………….. aware of the dangers of smoking.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "should",
                "be",
                "should be"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ………………………… for Alice.",
            "description": "A past verb is used after a past reporting verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is waiting",
                "was waiting",
                "will be waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ………………………… a job.",
            "description": "A present perfect in the direct speech will become past perfect in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "found",
                "has found",
                "had found"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she …………………………. for ages.",
            "description": "A present perfect continuous in the direct speech will become past perfect continuous in the indirect speech.",
            "answers": [
                "was waiting",
                "had been waiting",
                "has been waiting"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "He said that he ……………………….. meat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "has never eaten",
                "had never eaten",
                "never eats"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}